<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jacob's Website</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/tags/tiling-window-managers/</link><description> Recent Content on tiling-window-managers</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 10:41:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jhilker1.github.io/tags/tiling-window-managers/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Best Tiling Window Managers For Beginners</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2021/12/the-best-tiling-window-managers-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2021/12/the-best-tiling-window-managers-for-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anyone who knows me knows that I like to use a tiling window manager whenever I can. Having the ability to organize my programs into general categories, combined with the fact that none of the windows were overlapping, makes development so much easier compared to using a floating window manager in my opinion. However, the sheer number of choices presented when I was researching which window manager to use made it incredibly overwhelming for me to figure out where to start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For absolute beginners to tiling window managers, I would suggest &lt;a href="https:regolith-linux.org">Regolith Linux&lt;/a>, which uses the i3 window manager on top of Ubuntu. I&amp;rsquo;d also suggest &lt;a href="https:docs.qtile.org">Qtile&lt;/a>, for anyone who would rather use a dynamic TWM rather than a manual one like i3. I&amp;rsquo;ve also heard that &lt;a href="https://github.com/Baskerville/bspwm">BSPWM&lt;/a> is good for beginners; however, along with basically being a shell script, BSPWM doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle keybindings, instead handing that off to an external program by the same author, &lt;a href="https://github.com/Baskerville/sxhkd">SXHKD&lt;/a>, or the Simple X HotKey Daemon. I also don&amp;rsquo;t have that much experience with it, hence why I&amp;rsquo;m not including as much about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i3 is nice (and especially the Regolith config), because it gives you everything you need to get started learning (most) tiling window managers along with a way of checking your keybindings while in the window manager. However, i3 is written in its own language and not a traditional programming language, which means you&amp;rsquo;ll need an extra package or plugin for syntax highlighting in your text editor of choice (whether Vim or Emacs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also like Qtile because I don&amp;rsquo;t manually have to set up layouts the way I would with i3, and because it&amp;rsquo;s written in Python, which means that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to configure. It also means it&amp;rsquo;s easy to hack on to, so for instance you could create custom layouts that aren&amp;rsquo;t already available, or custom modules for the bar, etc. My personal favorite features are the ease of configuration, and the layouts feature like I said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you are interested in trying out a tiling window manager, install Regolith Linux and try out either i3 (which it uses) or install Qtile and try it out.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>