<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jacob's Website</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/tags/software/</link><description> Recent Content on software</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 10:41:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jhilker1.github.io/tags/software/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Best Tiling Window Managers For Beginners</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2021/12/the-best-tiling-window-managers-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2021/12/the-best-tiling-window-managers-for-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anyone who knows me knows that I like to use a tiling window manager whenever I can. Having the ability to organize my programs into general categories, combined with the fact that none of the windows were overlapping, makes development so much easier compared to using a floating window manager in my opinion. However, the sheer number of choices presented when I was researching which window manager to use made it incredibly overwhelming for me to figure out where to start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For absolute beginners to tiling window managers, I would suggest &lt;a href="https:regolith-linux.org">Regolith Linux&lt;/a>, which uses the i3 window manager on top of Ubuntu. I&amp;rsquo;d also suggest &lt;a href="https:docs.qtile.org">Qtile&lt;/a>, for anyone who would rather use a dynamic TWM rather than a manual one like i3. I&amp;rsquo;ve also heard that &lt;a href="https://github.com/Baskerville/bspwm">BSPWM&lt;/a> is good for beginners; however, along with basically being a shell script, BSPWM doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle keybindings, instead handing that off to an external program by the same author, &lt;a href="https://github.com/Baskerville/sxhkd">SXHKD&lt;/a>, or the Simple X HotKey Daemon. I also don&amp;rsquo;t have that much experience with it, hence why I&amp;rsquo;m not including as much about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>i3 is nice (and especially the Regolith config), because it gives you everything you need to get started learning (most) tiling window managers along with a way of checking your keybindings while in the window manager. However, i3 is written in its own language and not a traditional programming language, which means you&amp;rsquo;ll need an extra package or plugin for syntax highlighting in your text editor of choice (whether Vim or Emacs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also like Qtile because I don&amp;rsquo;t manually have to set up layouts the way I would with i3, and because it&amp;rsquo;s written in Python, which means that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to configure. It also means it&amp;rsquo;s easy to hack on to, so for instance you could create custom layouts that aren&amp;rsquo;t already available, or custom modules for the bar, etc. My personal favorite features are the ease of configuration, and the layouts feature like I said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you are interested in trying out a tiling window manager, install Regolith Linux and try out either i3 (which it uses) or install Qtile and try it out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Multireddits with Newsboat</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2020/12/multireddits-newsboat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:12:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2020/12/multireddits-newsboat/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Reddit, multireddits are a way of grouping multiple subreddits into a grouped feed. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to keep my reddit organized so I can view the content that I really want to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, here is what my gaming-related feed in newsboat looks like:&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="img/subreddit_query.png" alt="subreddit_query.png" width="60%" />
That is incredibly overwhelming, even if it is sorted by the date the post was published.
&lt;p>In my opinion, even keeping all the gaming subreddits I follow in a query feed could quickly become overwhelming since I follow a lot of game-related subreddits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use some of the Crusader Kings and Destiny-related subreddits I follow for a gaming multireddit, but you can use whatever you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To start with, I created a multireddit for all the Crusader Kings-related content I wanted to follow. I called it &amp;ldquo;crusaderkings&amp;rdquo;, but feel free to call it whatever you want. Once I had done that, I added several of the subreddits I wanted to follow - namely &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/CrusaderKings">CrusaderKings&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/CrusaderCharacters">CrusaderCharacters&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/CKTinder">CKTinder&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/ck3_dnas">CK3_DNAs&lt;/a>. While this list will most likely be updated in the future, four feeds is good enough for a start. Rinse and repeat this for whatever else you want to group together - for instance, maybe you follow several subreddits for a particular programming language. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s limitless what you can group by.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you add your individual subreddits to your multireddit, it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly easy to get an rss feed of you multireddit - just add &amp;ldquo;.rss&amp;rdquo; to the end of the url. Want to change your sorting order to be with the newest posts first? Just add &amp;ldquo;/new.rss&amp;rdquo; to your url. While searching can get a tiny bit more difficult, it really isn&amp;rsquo;t that much more difficult. Only want text posts? Search &amp;ldquo;self:yes&amp;rdquo;, and add &amp;ldquo;.rss&amp;rdquo; just before your query and just after the search in the url. As an example, the Crusader Kings multireddit I&amp;rsquo;m using here is &lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/user/jacobhilker1/m/crusaderkings.rss">https://old.reddit.com/user/jacobhilker1/m/crusaderkings.rss&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, simply add the RSS url to your newsboat URLs file (usually &lt;code>~/.newsboat/urls&lt;/code>) and you will get this when you view your multireddit feed (with my config, at least - yours may differ based on your &lt;code>articlelist-view.&lt;/code>):&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="img/default_multi.png" width="60%"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>While I&amp;rsquo;d like to print the exact subreddit each post is from, I am not entirely sure how to do that without adding some sort of tag for each multireddit. If I find a way to do that, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, I want to group my multireddits based on a certain category. Here is an example of what mine looks like, but yours may vary based on your configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="img/group_multi_index.png" width="60%"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Here is what it looks like when browsing a query feed:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="img/multi_feed_view.png" width="60%"/>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>