<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jacob's Website</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/categories/newsboat/</link><description> Recent Content on Newsboat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:12:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jhilker1.github.io/categories/newsboat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Multireddits with Newsboat</title><link>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2020/12/multireddits-newsboat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:12:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jhilker1.github.io/blog/2020/12/multireddits-newsboat/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Reddit, multireddits are a way of grouping multiple subreddits into a grouped feed. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to keep my reddit organized so I can view the content that I really want to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, here is what my gaming-related feed in newsboat looks like:&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="img/subreddit_query.png" alt="subreddit_query.png" width="60%" />
That is incredibly overwhelming, even if it is sorted by the date the post was published.
&lt;p>In my opinion, even keeping all the gaming subreddits I follow in a query feed could quickly become overwhelming since I follow a lot of game-related subreddits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use some of the Crusader Kings and Destiny-related subreddits I follow for a gaming multireddit, but you can use whatever you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To start with, I created a multireddit for all the Crusader Kings-related content I wanted to follow. I called it &amp;ldquo;crusaderkings&amp;rdquo;, but feel free to call it whatever you want. Once I had done that, I added several of the subreddits I wanted to follow - namely &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/CrusaderKings">CrusaderKings&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/CrusaderCharacters">CrusaderCharacters&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/CKTinder">CKTinder&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/ck3_dnas">CK3_DNAs&lt;/a>. While this list will most likely be updated in the future, four feeds is good enough for a start. Rinse and repeat this for whatever else you want to group together - for instance, maybe you follow several subreddits for a particular programming language. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s limitless what you can group by.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you add your individual subreddits to your multireddit, it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly easy to get an rss feed of you multireddit - just add &amp;ldquo;.rss&amp;rdquo; to the end of the url. Want to change your sorting order to be with the newest posts first? Just add &amp;ldquo;/new.rss&amp;rdquo; to your url. While searching can get a tiny bit more difficult, it really isn&amp;rsquo;t that much more difficult. Only want text posts? Search &amp;ldquo;self:yes&amp;rdquo;, and add &amp;ldquo;.rss&amp;rdquo; just before your query and just after the search in the url. As an example, the Crusader Kings multireddit I&amp;rsquo;m using here is &lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/user/jacobhilker1/m/crusaderkings.rss">https://old.reddit.com/user/jacobhilker1/m/crusaderkings.rss&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, simply add the RSS url to your newsboat URLs file (usually &lt;code>~/.newsboat/urls&lt;/code>) and you will get this when you view your multireddit feed (with my config, at least - yours may differ based on your &lt;code>articlelist-view.&lt;/code>):&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="img/default_multi.png" width="60%"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>While I&amp;rsquo;d like to print the exact subreddit each post is from, I am not entirely sure how to do that without adding some sort of tag for each multireddit. If I find a way to do that, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, I want to group my multireddits based on a certain category. Here is an example of what mine looks like, but yours may vary based on your configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="img/group_multi_index.png" width="60%"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Here is what it looks like when browsing a query feed:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="img/multi_feed_view.png" width="60%"/>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>